Guide to the Rockwell Kent Ephemera Collection, 1920-1995
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Rockwell Kent Ephemera Collection
1920-1995
Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971
0.2 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Primarily printed material relating to or including Kent's work.
Biographical Note
Rockwell Kent (1882-1971) was a painter, illustrator and printmaker.
Scope and Content Note
Primarily printed material relating to or including Kent's work, including exhibition catalogs, christmas cards, promotional material and more.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
For more information on, and materials produced by the Open Road Inc., see
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers, Folder 92.24
Separated Materials
Some published materials were removed from this collection to be cataloged. For works illustrated by Rockwell Kent, please consult the
Vassar College Online Catalog
.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Artists--United States--20th century; Illustrators, American
Document Types:
Ephemera
VCL Categories
Art and Artists; Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, June 2009.
Acquisition Information
This is an artificial collection compiled by the Vassar College Library over a number of years.
At least some portion of the collection was a gift of Arthur H. Groten.
Container List
- Christmas card fragment — "Still the breath does move...,", 1920 (Folder 1)
- Clipping from the Pittsburgh Gazette about Carnegie Institute Exhibit, 5 July 1924 (Folder 2)
- Exhibition catalog — Carnegie Institute, [1924] (Folder 3)
- Christmas card, 1926 (Folder 4)
- Weyhe Gallery catalog for Wanda Gág's work (with introduction by Kent), [1926] (Folder 5)
- Exhibition catalog — Wildenstein and Co., 1927 (Folder 6)
- Program for the 3rd Annual Exhibition of the American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1928 (Folder 7)
- Stationery for The Open Road, Inc.., [ca. 1928] (Folder 8)
- Promotional leaflet for Later Bookplates and Marks of Rockwell Kent, 1937 (Folder 9)
- U.S. postage stamps featuring a Rockwell Kent design, 1939 (Folder 10)
- Proof cards for [The Mountains Wait], [ca. 1942]; (2 sets of 4 cards) (Folder 11)
- Matchbook cover advertising Asgaard Dairy, [ca. 1948] (Folder 12)
- Promotional leaflet for Kent as a lecturer, Columbia Lecture Bureau, [ca. 1940s] (Folder 13)
- Program for the Explorer's Club 46th Annual Dinner, 1950 (Folder 14)
- Christmas card from Rockwell and Sally Kent, 1962 or Later (Folder 15)
- Program from the Essex County (NY) Historical Society Kent Exhibit, 1971 (Folder 16)
- Christmas card — "Ice Floes, Newfoundland,", 1973 (Folder 17)
- Catalog for Kent print sale by Associated American Artists, 1975 (Folder 18)
- Invitation for Kent exhibition at Larcada Gallery (New York), 1975 (Folder 19)
- Catalogue for the Center for Music, Drama and Art exhibit of Kent Christmas cards, 1977 (Folder 20)
- Christie's auction catalogue — "Rockwell Kent and Other Modern Illustrators,", 1995 (Folder 21)
- Advertising card for Kent, reading, "Architectural and General Designing and Rendering in Any Medium," (Folder 22)
- Advertising card for Asgaard Dairy, n.d. (Folder 23)
- Advertising card for Asgaard Flour, n.d. (Folder 24)
- Bookmark for the American Cancer Society, n.d. (Folder 25)
- Advertising card for Kent "On Earth Peace" Stamp, n.d. (Folder 26)
- Christmas card — [Angel over sheath of wheat], n.d. (Folder 27)
- Christmas card — "Books Make the Home,", n.d. (Folder28)
- Christmas card — "Designed for the Friends of Lenthéric," (Folder 29)
- Christmas card — "To the Universe,", n.d. (Folder 30)
- Christmas card — Printed for the American Artists Group, n.d. (Folder 31)
- Christmas card — "On Earth Peace,", n.d. (Folder 32)
- Christmas postcard for Provident Mutual Life Insurance — "Winter,", n.d. (Folder 33)
- Fragment — Christmas scene [cut from a magazine?], n.d. (Folder 34)
- Greeting card — "Heavy Heavy Hangs Over Thy Head.", n.d. (Folder 35)